A Guide to the James M. Scott Papers, 1975-1981
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The James M. Scott Papers, 1975-1981
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 06-62
0.5 linear feet
The James M. Scott Papers consist of 0.5 linear feet, spanning the years 1975 to 1981, during Scott’s time with the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors. The files consist of correspondence, reports, and documents related to local land use regulations, fiscal management in Northern Virginia counties, national urban policy, sewer service rates in Fairfax County, and water supply management in Metropolitan Washington.
Scott, James M. (1938-2017)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by Merrily Peirce on December 23, 2003. Files came from Chairman Kate Hanley’s office who inherited the files of her predecessor, James M. Scott. Scott’s files were later purged with the exception of these papers.
Historical and Biographical Information
James “Jim” Martin Scott was born on June 11, 1938 in Galax, Virginia. After graduating from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill with a B.A. in English in 1960 and a M.A. in English in 1965, Scott briefly worked as a high school teacher for Arlington Public Schools. He then went on to work for several community organizations including United Planning Organization, Fairfax Community Action Program, and Washington Suburban Institute.
In 1972, Jim Scott was elected to the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors where he served until 1984. During this time Scott was also involved in several civic organizations, serving on the Executive Board of the Virginia Association of Counties and on the Community Resources Policy Committee for the Washington Metropolitan Council of Governments. He then worked for Inova Health Systems before running for delegate in 1991. For the remainder of his career, Scott served as Virginia State Delegate for the 53rd District of Virginia for 22 years from 1991 to 2013. In 2017, Scott passed away in Springfield, VA due to complications from Alzheimer’s disease.
Scope and Content
The James M. Scott Papers consist of 0.5 linear feet, spanning the years 1975 to 1981, during Scott’s time with the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors. The files consist of correspondence, reports, and documents related to local land use regulations, fiscal management in Northern Virginia counties, national urban policy, sewer service rates in Fairfax County, and water supply management in Metropolitan Washington.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fairfax County (Va.). Board of Supervisors; Fairfax County (Va.) -- Officials and employees; Fairfax County (Va.) -- Politics and government; Scott, James M. (1938-2017)
Container List
- Amendment of Local Land Use Regulation, Adequate Public Facilities Ordinance [Correspondence and Legislation], 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fairfax County Park Authority, Highlights for 1975, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Fiscal Management - Virginia Association of Counties, Memorandums, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Fiscal Management - Virginia Association of Counties and Virginia Municipal League, Correspondence and Related Documents, 1981, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Fiscal Management - Legislation Affecting Local Government, Virginia Municipal League, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fiscal Management - Statewide Salary Survey, Virginia Municipal League, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Fiscal Management - Local Government Financial Management Capacity Sharing Program Plan [Draft], 1981 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
- National Urban Policy, Correspondence and Final Report of the Urban and Regional Policy Group, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sewer Service Rates - County of Fairfax Board of Supervisors, Correspondence and Memorandums, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sewer Service Rates - Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Water Supply - Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments, Meeting Minutes and Regional Report, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Water Supply - Metropolitan Washington Water Resources Planning Board, Reports on Potomac River Pollution and Sampling, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Water Supply - Metropolitan Washington Water Supply Emergency Agreement, Testimony and Remarks by James M. Scott, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Water Supply - Metropolitan Washington Water Supply Emergency Agreement, 1979 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Water Supply - Guidebook for Screening Urban Nonpoint Pollution Management Strategies [Draft Copy], 1979 November (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Water Supply - Metropolitan Washington Water Resources Planning Board, Proposed Resolution and Amendments to Federal Clean Water Act, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)